Guide to the American Society of Planning Officials Records, 1925-1982
American Society of Planning Officials Records, 1925-1982
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
American Society of Planning Officials records, 1925-1982
3247
American Society of Planning Officials
43 cubic ft.
Minutes, reports, correspondence, memoranda, membership lists, conference proceedings, articles, drafts, a book manuscript, newsletters, bulletins, newspaper clippings, other printed materials, and audiotapes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes files of the American Society of Planning Officials (ASPO) and material on the activities of other professional planning organizations, including topics of education and job opportunities for minorities and women in planning, professional ethics, awards, transportation, community improvement, and zoning. Also included are records of the Dennis O'Harrow Memorial Fund, and a manuscript for a book about O'Harrow; and files of or about Walter Blucher, Harvey S. Perloff, and Israel Stollman.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of the American Society of Planning Officials (ASPO) consist primarily of minutes, reports, correspondence, and memoranda, as well as membership lists; conference proceedings; and articles, drafts, newsletters, bulletins, newspaper clippings, and other printed materials concerning Board of Directors' and annual meetings; history of ASPO activities; ASPO committees, policies, and programs; activities of other professional planning organizations, including the American City Planning Institute, American Institute of Planners, American Society of City Planners, Association of State Planning and Development Agencies, International Federation of Housing and Town Planners (later International Federation of Housing and Planning), the North American Regional Section of IFHP (NARS), Public Administration Clearing House and the Public Administration Service, the National Resources Committee, the National Industrial Zoning Committee, and Jaycees; AIP/ASPO/ASCP joint committees; the 1978 AIP/ASPO merger (forming the American Planning Association); the Alfred Bettman Foundation; the Spellman Fund; Honorary Life Members files, including biographical data and obituaries of ASPO members; and many topics relating to the planning profession, including education and job opportunities for minorities and women in planning, professional ethics, awards, transportation, community improvement, and zoning.
Also included are records pertaining to the Dennis O'Harrow Memorial Fund, research materials and a manuscript for a book about O'Harrow; and files of or about Walter Blucher, Harvey S. Perloff, and Israel Stollman.
SUBJECTS
Names:
American Society of Planning Officials; Blucher, Walter H. (Walter Harold), 1901-; O'Harrow, Dennis, 1908-; Perloff, Harvey S.; Stollman, Israel.; Alfred Bettman Foundation.; American City Planning Institute.; American Institute of Planners.; American Society of City Planners.; Association of State Planning and Development Agencies (U.S.).; International Federation for Housing and Town Planning.; Jaycees International.; National Industrial Zoning Committee (U.S.).; Public Administration Clearing House.; Public Administration Service.; United States. National Resources Committee.
Subjects:
City planning.; City planning and redevelopment law.; Minorities--Education.; Planners.; Planners--Education.; Professional education of women.; Professional ethics.; Regional planning.; Social policy.; Transportation--Planning.; Universities and colleges--Accreditation.; Women--Education.
Form and Genre Terms:
Speeches.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
See also: Guide to the American Planning Association Records ( collection #4075) and the Guide to the American Institute of Planners Records ( collection #4007).
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Planning publications (Boxes 1-11) are arranged chronologically.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Printed material
Boxes 1-9, 11
Series II. National Industrial Zoning Committee
Box 10
Series III. ASPO board and committees, 1934-1978
Boxes 12-17
Series IV. ASPO history of activities (and miscellaneous files)
Boxes 18-25
Series V. Files of Dennis O'Harrow (including materials regarding a book and memorial dedicated to O'Harrow)
Box es 26-29
Series VI. ASPO honorary life members files
Boxes 30-33
Series VII. ASPO files regarding the American Institute of Planners
Boxes 34-36
Series VIII. ASPO files regarding Association of State Planning and Development Agencies
Boxes 37-38
Series IX. ASPO files regarding International Federation for Housing and Town Planning (later International Federation for Housing and Planning)
Boxes 39-42
Series X. Audiotapes of Hugh Pomeroy
Tape drawer
Series XI. Photographs
Oversize Folder
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Printed material
  - Planning Advisory Service, No. 1-109 (11 volumes), April 1949-April 1958 (Box 1)
  - Planning Advisory Service, No. 110-229 (1 volume, 10 binders), May 1958-December 1967 (Box 2)
  - Planning Advisory Service, No. 230-274 (4 binders), Jan. 1968-Nov. 1971 (Box 3)
  - ASPO Land-Use Controls Quarterly, volumes 1-4, (16 numbers), 1967-1970 (Box 3)
  - American Society of Planning Officials Newsletter, volumes 1-20 (20 volumes), February 1935-November 1954 (Box 4)
  - American Society of Planning Officials Newsletter, volumes 21-30 (10 volumes), January 1955-Dedember 1965 (Box 5)
  - Index, volume 3-25 (1 binder) (Box 5)
  - Zoning decisions, index to decisions in ASPO Newsletter, (1 binder), 1935-1948 (Box 5)
  - Planning (11 volumes), 1935-1940, 1941-1942, 1944-1947 (Box 5)
  - Planning (22 volumes), 1948, 1950-1955, 1957-1971 (Box 6)
  - ASPO publications and distributions, 1930-1959 (Box 7)
  - ASPO publications and distributions, 1960-1969 (Box 8)
  - ASPO publications and distributions, ca. 1970's, no date (Box 9)
  - Planning Advisory Service, No. 286-319, (30 volumes). Index, 1977, December 1972-August 1975 (Box 11)
  - ASPO Newsletters, various dates (Box 43-44)
  - Jobs in Planning (TAB), January 1966-December 1978, November 1981-December 1982 (Box 45)
- Series II. National Industrial Zoning Committee
  - Records of the National Industrial Zoning Committee (NIZC), 1949-1952 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - NIZC, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - NIZC, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - NIZC, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - NIZC, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - NIZC, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - NIZC, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - NIZC, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - NIZC, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 9-10)
  - NIZC, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - NIZC, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - NIZC, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - NIZC, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - NIZC, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - NIZC, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - NIZC, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Series III. ASPO board and committees, 1934-1978
  - ASPO board meetings - minutes, 1934-1942 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - ASPO board meetings - minutes, 1943-1952 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - ASPO board meetings - minutes, 1953-1958 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - ASPO board meetings - minutes, 1959-1966 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - ASPO board meetings - minutes, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - ASPO board meetings - minutes, 1969-1971 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - ASPO board meetings - minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - ASPO board meetings - minutes, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - ASPO board meetings - minutes, 1976-1978 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1934-1935 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1936-1937 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1942-1943 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - ASPO minutes and reports to directors, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Toronto, Apr. 1965 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Oct. 1965 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Feb. 1966 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Philidelphia, Apr. 1966 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Nov. 1966 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Houston, Apr. 1967 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Sept. 1967 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Washington, October 1967 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 50th Anniversary Award presented by AIP, October 1967; Oversize folder
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, November 1967 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Jan. 1968-Nov. 1971 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Mar. 1968 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, San Francisco, May-68 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Feb. 1969 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Cincinnati, Apr. 1969 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Sept. 1969 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Feb. 1970 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, New York, Apr. 1970 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Joint Board Meeting, ASPO-AIP, New York, Apr. 1970 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Sept. 1970 (Box 13, Folder 19-20)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, New York, Apr. 1970 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Jan. 1971 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, New Orleans, Mar. 1971 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Sept. 1971 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Feb. 1972 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Detroit, Apr. 1972 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Boston, Oct. 1972 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Jan. 1973 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Los Angeles, Apr. 1973 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Atlanta, Oct. 1973 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Jan. 1974 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, May-74 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Annual Meeting, Chicago, May-74 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Denver, Oct. 1974 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - "Directions for Public Planning in the 80's", 1975 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Jan. - Feb. 1975 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Vancouver, Apr. 1975 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Sept. 1975 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Washington, Mar. 1976 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Sept. 1976 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, San Diego, Apr. 1977 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Chicago, Jul. 1977 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Kansas City, Oct. 1977 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Indianapolis, Apr. 1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Board Addresses (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Board Lists (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Board Sample Certificate (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Board Sample Memos (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Board Student Certificates (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Memoranda, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Memoranda, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Memoranda, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Memoranda, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Memoranda, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Memoranda, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Memoranda, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Memoranda, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Memoranda, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Memoranda, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Memoranda, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Memoranda, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Memoranda, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Memoranda, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Memoranda, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Memoranda, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO/ASCP Education Committee - Criteria for recognitions of schools (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO/ASCP Education Committee - Legislative committee (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO/ASCP Education Committee (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO/API Liasion Committee (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO Education Committee (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO International Committee (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO Liasion Committee (Box 14, Folder 32-34)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO Merger (Box 14, Folder 35-36)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO Merger (Box 15, Folder 1-11)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO Minority Affairs (Box 15, Folder 12-13)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO Merger - Teller Committee (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO Conference - Policy Committee (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO Tranportation Planning Committee (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Committees: AIP/ASPO Women's rights (Box 15, Folder 17-18)
  - Committees: background information (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Committees: lists (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Committees: Amicus Curiae Committee (Box 15, Folder 21-23)
  - Committees: Budget and Finance Committee (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Committees: Conference Evaluation Task Force (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Committees: Development Plan and Budget Committee (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Committees: Education Committee (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Committees: Energy Committee (never organized) (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Committees: Education Committee Junior and Community College Curricula (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Committees: Ethics Committee - "A Code of Ethics in Planning" (Box 15, Folder 30-33)
  - Committees: Ethics Committee (Fairfax County scandal) (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Committees: Ethics Committee (Fairfax County scandal) (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Committees: Ethics Committee (Honolulu code of ethics) (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Committees: Ethics Committee (Iowa City scandal) (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Committees: Ethics Committee (Montgomery County scandal) (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Committees: Ethics Committee (Omaha scandal) (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Committees: Ethics Committee (practice of law) (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Committees: Ethics Committee (preparation of code), 1961-1962 (Box 15, Folder 41-42)
  - Committees: Ethics Committee (preparation of code), 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Committees: Ethics Committee (preparation of code), 1963-1966 (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
  - Committees: Ethics Committee (St. Louis scandal) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Committees: Executive Committee (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Committees: Fellowship Committee (background) (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Committees: Fellowship Committee (losers) (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
  - Committees: Fellowship Committee (miscellaneous) (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Committees: Fellowship Committee (selection committee) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Committees: Fellowship Committee (winners) (Box 16, Folder 12-13)
  - Committees: Fellowship Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 16, Folder 14-20)
  - Committees: Fellowship Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 21-25)
  - Committees: Implementation Committee (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Committees: Medal Award Committee (background) (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Committees: Medal Award Committee (citations) (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Committees: Medal Award Committee (list of recipients) (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Committees: Medal Award Committee (miscellaneous) (Box 16, Folder 30-32)
  - Committees: Member Services Committee (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Committees: Minority Affairs Council (Box 16, Folder 34-38)
  - Committees: National Growth Policy Committee (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee (background) (Box 16, Folder 40-41)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee (Certification Committee) (Box 16, Folder 42-44)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee (forms) (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee (list of members) (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee (new prospects) (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee (petition) (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 6-8)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 9-10)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 11-14)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 16-17)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Committees: Nominating Committee, 1962-1968 (Box 17, Folder 19-20)
  - Committees: North American Regional Section Committee (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (Box 17, Folder 22-24)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (background) (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (Highway Beautification Act) (Box 17, Folder 26-28)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (Junior and Community Colleges) (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: Sept. 4, 1969, Chicago), 1969 (Box 17, Folder 30-31)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: Apr. 18, 1969, Cincinnati), 1969 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: Feb. 20, 1969), 1969 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: Oct. 16, 1968, Pittsburgh), 1968 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: May 3, 1968, San Fransisco), 1968 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: Oct. 31, 1967), 1967 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: Apr. 1, 1967, Houston), 1967 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: Nov. 9, 1966, Chicago), 1966 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: Feb. 11, 1966, Chicago), 1966 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: Mar. 26-27, 1963, Chicago), 1965 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: Oct. 13, 1965, Chicago), 1963 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: May 3, 1962, Atlantic City), 1962 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: Jan. 30-31, 1962, Chicago), 1962 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (meeting: May 2, 1961, Denver), 1961 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Committees: Policy and Program Committee (folder left by Majorie S. Berger) (Box 17, Folder 45-50)
  - Committees: Public Relations (Box 17, Folder 51)
  - Committees: Publications (Box 17, Folder 52)
  - Committees: Regional Conference Committee (Box 17, Folder 53)
  - Committees: Registration of Planners Committee (Box 17, Folder 54)
  - Committees: Research Committee (Box 17, Folder 55)
  - Committees: Tax-Abandoned Land Committee (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - Committees: Terminology Committee (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - Committees: Women's Issues Task Force (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - Committees: Zoning Digest - Land Use Controls Committee (Box 17, Folder 59)
- Series IV. ASPO history of activities (and miscellaneous files)
  - Back to the Farm clippings, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Bandon-by-the-Sea clippings, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Better Chicago contest, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - "Blighted Areas" clippings, 1936-1940 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Budget clippings, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Building Booms clippings, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Canadian planning clippings, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Capital Improvement Program clippings, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Census clippings, 1935-1940 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - International Exposition - Internationale De L'urbanisine et de L'Habitation, Paris, 1946-1947 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - The Alinsky Affair: clippings regarding Industrial Relations Foundation and the Woodlawn Organization, 1961-1964 (Box 18, Folder 11-15)
  - National Resources Committee, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 16-17)
  - National Resources Committee, 1938-1939 (Box 18, Folder 18-19)
  - Alfred Bettman, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - National Resources Committee "Report on the Status of State Planning", 1937 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - National Resources Committee, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 22-24)
  - National Resources Committee-Proceedings of the Summary Session of the National Zoning Conference, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 24A)
  - National Resources Committee, 1935 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - National Committee on Urban Transportation, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - National Committee on Urban Transportation, Planning Methods, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - National Committee on Urban Transportation, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 28-30)
  - National Committee on Urban Transportation, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 31-32)
  - National Committee on Urban Transportation, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 33-34)
  - National Committee on Urban Transportation, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - National Committee on Urban Transportation, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - National Advisory Committee on Air Pollution, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 37-39)
  - Illinois Post-War Planning Commission - Committees, A-I, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Illinois Post-War Planning Commission - Committees, L, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Illinois Post-War Planning Commission - Committees, P-Z, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Illinois Post-War Planning Commission - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Illinois Post-War Planning Commission, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Jaycees - Minutes and Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Jaycees - Minutes and Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Jaycees - Minutes and Correspondence, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - American Studies Association, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - Jaycees, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - Conference on Metropolitan Area Problems, 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 50)
  - Conference on Metropolitan Area Problems, 1957-1958 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Conference on Metropolitan Area Problems, 1955-1956 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Council of Metropolitan Regional Organizations (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - International Union of Local Authorities, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Interprofessional Urban Planning Committee, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Interprofessional Urban Planning Committee, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 6)